<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Elizabeth Karan</title><link>eakaran.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Elizabeth Karan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="eakaran.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About me</title><link>eakaran.github.io/post/home/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>eakaran.github.io/post/home/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m Liz Karan, an evolutionary biologist whose work aims to understand how the diversity we observe across reef fishes came to be. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in comparative methods, developing high-throughput tools for macroevolutionary studies, and ecological applications of machine learning. I&amp;rsquo;m currently a PhD Candidate at the University of California, Los Angeles with Michael Alfaro, PhD.</description></item><item><title>Curriculum vitae</title><link>eakaran.github.io/cv/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>eakaran.github.io/cv/</guid><description>Elizabeth Karan&amp;rsquo;s CV (pdf)
EDUCATION
PH.D. IN ECOLOGY AND EVOLUTIONARY BIOLOGY, 2017–PRESENT
UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, LOS ANGELES; LOS ANGELES, CA A.B. ORGANISMIC AND EVOLUTIONARY BIOLOGY, 2016
HARVARD COLLEGE; CAMBRIDGE, MA RESEARCH EXPERIENCE
PH.D. CANDIDATE, ALFARO LAB; LOS ANGELES, CA 2021–PRESENT PH.D. STUDENT, ALFARO LAB; LOS ANGELES, CA 2017– 2020 UNDERGRADUATE RESEARCHER, LAUDER LAB; CAMBRIDGE, MA 2015–2016 RESEARCH ASSISTANT, RADCLIFFE RESEARCH PARTNERSHIP; CAMBRIDGE, MA 2015 VOLUNTEER, MUSEUM OF COMPARATIVE ZOOLOGY; CAMBRIDGE, MA 2014–2016 RESEARCH ASSISTANT, OPERATION WALLACEA; WAKATOBI N.</description></item><item><title>Research</title><link>eakaran.github.io/research/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>eakaran.github.io/research/</guid><description>Coral reef fishes comprise one of the most conspicuously colorful assemblages of vertebrates on Earth. The diversity of color mechanisms and color patterns are axes of diversity to consider within speciation and evolutionary history, however the overall diversity has never been quantified broadly across fishes. Although previous studies have linked diversity of color and color patterns in reef fish to factors ranging from sexual selection and communication with conspecifics to predator-prey interactions, these hypotheses have not been tested in a comparative macroevolutionary framework.</description></item></channel></rss>